AÍDA BENITO

anbenito@yahoo.com.ar

Quilmes, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Cell: (54 9 11) 6-497-6858 - Skype: anbenito1975@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aida-benito/

INFORMATION SYSTEMS ENGINEER

Experienced Data Engineer and Business Intelligence Consultant. Possesses advanced knowledge of databases and various BI tools, as well as knowledge of programming languages, AWS and GCP Ecosystems. Has strong communication skills. Passionate about Data Science, Big Data, Internet of Things, Artificial Intelligence, research and learning. Able to handle several projects simultaneously. Has passed the *First Certificate in English* exam.

Core competencies include:

Flexibility - Leadership - Teamwork - Conflict resolution - Analytical thinking - Decision making

Customer Service - Creative thinking

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MPS Group - Client: Delta Airlines

Data Engineer (January 2024 - May 2024)

- Design and propose architecture solutions
- Develop ETL components
- Develop SQL queries

Python - Postgres - AWS (S3, Secrets Manager, CloudWatch, EventBridge, Lambda, Step Functions, RDS, CodeCommit, CDK) - GitLab

Leniolabs – Client: Intercontinental Exchange

Data Scientist (July 2022 – October 2022)

- Develop new features for deployment pipeline
- Investigate and analyze solutions to optimize deployment strategies
- Investigate and analyze solutions to use AWS CloudFormation to deploy SageMaker endpoints

Python – AWS (S3, SageMaker, CloudFormation) – Jenkins – GIT – Jira

Leniolabs - Client: PayPal

Data Engineer (September 2021 – June 2022)

- Analyze requirements and propose solutions
- Develop new features to existing Frameworks
- Run data load processes (Pre Production and Production environments)

Python - Google Cloud Platform (GCS, BigQuery) - Github - Jira

<u>Darwoft – Client: CareJourney</u> Big Data project. HealthTech

Data Engineer (February 2021 – September 2021)

- Analyze and document existing processes
- Create technical specifications documents
- Migrate Glue jobs to be able to run them using Airflow and Snowflake
- Run data load processes (Production environment)
- Validate data loads

Airflow - Python - Pyspark - Snowflake - AWS - Hive - Presto - Postgres - GitHub - Jira

Corebi - Client: AON

The goal of the project was to create a regional analytical platform.

Data Engineer Lead (October 2020 – January 2021)

- Plan sprint
- Estimate the effort for the tasks to be performed.
- Design data models Refined Layer
- Define required tools
- Develop, test and maintain data pipelines
- Train coworkers

Cloudera – Impala – AWS (S3) – PySpark – Cloudera Data Science Workbench

One employee under my supervision

<u>Corebi – Client: The Marketing Store</u>

Big Data project.

Data Engineer (September 2019 – September 2020)

- Develop scripts and create new Glue jobs
- Develop new features to existing Glue Jobs
- Fix Production issues

Python - Pyspark - AWS (Glue, S3, Athena, Simple Queue Service) - Jira - Bitbucket - MySQL

Softtek - Client: AB InBev

The goals of the project were to standardize and optimize various business processes and, also, design and create a new data warehouse to support them. The scope included five countries.

Business Intelligence Functional / Technical Analyst (January 2017 – March 2018)

- Estimate the effort for the tasks to be performed.
- Have meetings with different stakeholders (users, experts, project manager, among others)
- Analyze existing data warehouse.
- Analyze business processes.
- Analyze source systems.
- Analyze requirements.
- Determine gaps and propose improvements.
- Collaborate with the definition of the architecture of the new data warehouse.
- Design models for the new data warehouse.
- Elaborate the corresponding deliverables.

MS Office - Cognos Workflow Manager - PL/SQL developer - TOAD

Entrepeneurship - farmared

Team to design and develop a social network for the pharmaceutical field.

Programmer Analyst (August 2016 – March 2017)

- Analyze the needs of the pharmaceutical sector and determine the functional and nonfunctional requirements.
- Identify the stakeholders.
- Plan the tasks to achieve the goals of the project.
- Collaborate in the design of the solution.
- Develop the front end of the web application.

Wordpress - HTML - CSS - AngularJS - Javascript - Nodejs - Promises - GIT - WebStorm

Ministry of Modernization of the Argentine Nation

Its objective was to implement technology to modernize public

administration. BI consultant (April 2016 – July 2016)

- Have meetings with different stakeholders, in the Ministry of Finance, in Casa Rosada and in the Ministry of Modernization.
- Analyze the data available in the database, provided by the Ministry of Finance.
- Define criteria to debug principle tables of the database.
- Suggest ways to improve our work
- Analyze requirements
- Design and develop reports:
 - according to requirements of the Cabinet Office of Ministers

- in response to the needs of the different Directorates of the Ministry
- for being analyzed by the National Directorate of Information Management and Salary Policy, to accomplish the objectives that are within its competency

One employee under my supervision

Tableau – MS Access – SQL Developer (Oracle) – MS Office IBM – Client: Cablevisión

It was a software factory.

IT Specialist, BI Team Leader / BI Technical Leader (February 2015 – Jul 2015)

- Plan resources
- Manage incident, corrective and evolutionary
- Manage issues and risks
- Monitor the status of requirements
- Control fulfillment of deliveries in time and form
- Provide technical and functional support for the development team, the functional analysts and the testers
- Hold management and operational meetings with the customer

Fifteen employees under my supervision

PowerCenter – OBIEE – Teradata Studio – Teradata SQL Assistant – SQL Developer (Oracle) - MS Project – CVS – MS Office

IBM - Client: Cablevisión

It was a software factory.

IT Specialist, BI Programmer Analyst (March 2014 – January 2015)

- Elicit and analyze BI and Integration requirements.
- Create high level technical design documents.
- Estimate time effort for developing tasks.
- Develop and maintain ETL processes.
- Develop and maintain automatic, operational and analytical reports.
- Create detailed technical design documents.
- Research the tools used

PowerCenter – OBIEE – Teradata Studio – Teradata SQL Assistant – SQL Developer (Oracle) - MS Offic

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Education

<u>Universidad de Buenos Aires</u> Artificial Intelligence Specialist (in progress)

<u>Universidad Tecnológica Nacional</u> Information Systems Engineer – Graduated in August 2013.

Training and certifications

<u>Snowflake[A-Z] Zero to Hero Masterclass (Core+SQL+API+Visual)</u>
Udemy, 2021

Best practices for data processing in Big Data (Databricks)

Coursera, 2020

Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals

Coursera, 2020

Modernizing Data Lakes and Data Warehouses with GCP

Coursera, 2020

Big Data Analytics Using Spark

edX

Apache Airflow

Udemy, 2020

Python for Data Science

edX, 2019

CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript

edX, 2019 Machine Learning

Coursera, 2016

Oracle Business Intelligence Foundation Suite 11g Certified Implementation

Specialist Oracle, 2014

Open Smartflex

Open, 2014

Augmented Reality

Universidad Tecnológica Nacional, 2013

Languages skills

English

First Certificate in English